# RAJITA MAHARJAN

1210 Cedar Grove Dr, Raleigh, NC 27607 | (C) 347-233-7674 | rajita.maharjan@gmail.com

# **Professional Summary**

IT Professional with over 4 years of career experience in higher education service desk environment. Excellent customer service, troubleshooting, consulting, organizational and problem-solving skills. Demonstrated ability to work productively and efficiently with a diverse array of people in a team environment. Exhibits a dedicated work ethic and collegial demeanor.

To obtain the challenging and rewarding position where I can further my career as a full stack developer by using technologies like HTML, CSS, JavaScript/jQuery, firebase and Node.js to create intuitive and elegant applications.

#### **Technical Skills**

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript/jQuery
- Responsive design
- Node.js
- Firebase
- Ajax
- Rest Api

#### **Skills**

- Outstanding analytical, problem-solving, and troubleshooting abilities
- Adept at working both independently and within a team, as required
- Proficient in Office 365, Exchange, Active Directory, WordPress, Remedy, Service Now, PowerShell
- Great working knowledge of Windows, Mac OS, Android, and iOS
- Poised, patient, courteous, and friendly with clients and colleagues
- Exhibit a strong desire to learn and develop both technically and professionally

#### **Work History**

#### Coding Bootcamp

Oct 2018 - Present

- Designed and developed 10+ application using technologies like HTML, CSS, JavaScript/jQuery, firebase and Node.js.
- Collaborated with other developers on group project and established a project workflow using Github.

#### **Technology Support Analyst – Tier 2**

Nov 2017 - Present

UNC Chapel Hill, NC

- Support UNC customers in the use of applications and platforms like Active Directory, Exchange, Office 365, WordPress, Sakai, Connect Carolina, TIM, Windows, Mac OS, Android, and iOS.
- Mentor, assist, and communicate with Tier 1 team to maximize first call resolution for customers.
- Responsible for monitoring the Service Desk ticket queues to resolve, assign, and escalate tickets to appropriate personnel and functional areas within ITS and UNC computing infrastructure, in compliance with SLAs.
- Track and document all incidents and customer requests in Remedy. Work with colleagues and Tier 3 teams to identify patterns and problems. Develop and deploy fixes to resolve customer issues at first point of contact.
- Work with Tier 2 team on technical documents and data collection for internal special projects.

#### **Technology Support Analyst - Walk-in support**

Jun 2017 - Oct 2017

UNC Chapel Hill, NC

- Gathered incident descriptions from clients. Documented work and solutions using Remedy tracking system.
- Trained and mentored new student and full-time walk-in support staff at service desk.

- Performed software and hardware troubleshooting. Configured client computers and mobile devices.
- Provisioned and assisted customers with UNC technology services like Wi-Fi, email, printing, Office suite, Exchange, learning management systems, and specialized software packages.
- · Worked with colleagues and vendors to resolve and/or escalate software and hardware issues as defined by SLAs.

## **Help Desk Analyst – Office 365 migration field team**

Feb 2017 - Jun 2017

UNC Chapel Hill, NC

- Served as member of Office 365 migration field team to assist more than 30,000 UNC faculty and staff to migrate from on-premises Exchange system to Office 365 in accordance with migration SLAs.
- Developed Office 365 migration documentation for use by UNC customers.
- Provided customer service and technical support to customers at their sites during scheduled migration windows.
- Collaborated with UNC Service Desk Tier 1 and Tier 2 to identify and resolve migration patterns and problems.
- Troubleshot issues with Office 365 apps, calendars, mailboxes, and clients like Outlook, Mac Mail, Thunderbird.
- Supported network related issues on computing and mobile devices like Windows, Mac OS, iOS, Android.
- Assisted with Microsoft System Center Configuration Manager (SCCM) deployments via Active Directory.

## **Technical Support Specialist**

Feb 2016 - May 2016

Target Corporation, MN

- Used Service Now for documenting, tracking, and managing incidents and Service Requests.
- Diagnosed and resolved software and hardware related technical issues for customers.
- Performed network component, desktop, printer, and remote access troubleshooting.
- Used scripting skills to contribute to internal tools and automate labor-intensive processes.
- Managed incoming call flow and provided friendly and responsive technical support to all customers.
- Ensured quick resolution of customer concerns and escalated appropriate issues to field and senior service engineers.

#### **Deployment Student Lead Technician -Tier II**

Sep 2013 – Dec 2015

Dec 2015

Minnesota State University Moorhead, MN

- Provisioned, coordinated, and configured client computer setups, installations and upgrades.
- Deployed new workstations and printers, installed operating systems, applications, drivers, and configured network settings and hardware. Mapped printers and troubleshot connectivity issues.
- Ensured provisioned systems and their configurations met customer requirements in accordance with SLAs.
- Used SharePoint database to keep inventory of all stored, staged, and deployed departmental equipment.
- Deployed Active Directory user and groups policies for management of domain workstations.

## **Education**

Minnesota State University Moorhead - 1104 7th Ave S, Moorhead, MN 56563

**Bachelor's of Science: Healthcare Administration** 

**Minor: Management** 

**Certificate: Business Analytics**